MATT: I think one of the interesting
things is that autism is certainly
much more recognised now and
it's certainly recognised much
more in an educational setting.
When I was at primary school and
even at middle and high school, it
really wasn't spoken about at all.
The only thing that was ever really
spoken about in terms of yeah,
educational  difficulties was dyslexia.
And even that required
parents to be quite proactive.
I had a friend who was dyslexic
at primary school and I also had a
friend who was really dyslexic when
I went to university, but then the
children who were sort of only 10,
15 or so years younger than me were
starting to get diagnosed with autism.
So I do think there has been a great
improvement, it's being more recognised.
It is being treated more and
as I mentioned before, we are
starting to recognise that it
affects women and girls as well.
But that it presents in slightly
different ways because of the way
they're socialised and tend to have
much more effective masking strategies.
There is still, in terms of mental
health services, across the board a
kind of lack of funding and a lack
of provision and that seems to be
particularly the case for adults.
I have a friend who a little later
than me, last couple of years,
got a referral for an assessment.
And the waiting list, this was with the
same service in Trafford, the waiting
list for that was initially four years.
When he, he got his referral.
Though, I believe that's come down.
But like I say, in Greater Manchester,
as far as I know there are two to
sort of commissioning groups or
whatever they're called, that actually
do this assessment for adults.
So that's certainly an area where things
could be, could be very much improved.
I think  that's sort of the most important
thing that's on my mind at the moment.